<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Saliency | Ishita Tripathi</title><link>https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/tag/saliency/</link><atom:link href="https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/tag/saliency/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Saliency</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Saliency</title><link>https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/tag/saliency/</link></image><item><title>Maximum Points and Effort on the Test - Evidence from a Natural Field Experiment</title><link>https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/project/saliency/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/project/saliency/</guid><description>&lt;p>Students often exert low levels of effort on the test, especially in low-stake tests which may paint an incorrect image of their true learning levels. Offering pecuniary and non-pecuniary incentives may be effective in increasing such effort but often not feasible. Increasing the maximum points assigned to the test may be a supposedly irrelevant factor that can frame it as more valued, and nudge students to exert more effort on the test. Using a natural field experiment, we randomly assign 1235 students to a test framed as either carrying maximum 20-points or 100-points, and study its impact in both high-stake (comprising non-risky and one risky question) and low-stake (comprising only non-risky questions) test settings. While we find a small and statistically insignificant average treatment effect in both settings, we find positive treatment effects (1) among lower ability students in a low-stake test, (2) among higher ability students in a high-stake test only when the question carries the risk of a negative penalty. We discuss increased mental effort as the mechanism driving these effects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Working paper available on request&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>