<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ishita Tripathi</title><link>https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/</link><atom:link href="https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Ishita Tripathi</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Ishita Tripathi</title><link>https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/</link></image><item><title>Are terrorists responsible for anti-immigrant sentiments? Evidence from Europe</title><link>https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/project/antiimmigrant/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/project/antiimmigrant/</guid><description>&lt;p>Anti-immigrant sentiments are rising across the globe, influencing electoral results, economic policies, labour market outcomes, and even businesses. The factors influencing such sentiments range from socio-economic to cultural. In this paper, I study the impact of one such random shock – terrorism, on anti-immigrant attitudes. I utilise the variation in time and location of terrorist attacks to identify their effect. For this, I analyse the opinions of more than 250,000 individuals belonging to 32 European countries over the period 2002 to 2019. I find that there is around 4 percent decrease on average in an individual&amp;rsquo;s pro-immigrant attitudes after foreigners have carried out terrorist attacks in their country. But this detrimental effect disappears after 6 months and is more localised. My findings imply that inspite of being a relatively rare experience, exposure to terrorism can briefly prejudice an individual against immigrants, but only when the perpetrator(s) is of a different nationality. This can be helpful in understanding the factors leading to increased animosity against migrants.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S026499932200205X" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S026499932200205X&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Maximum Points and Effort on the Test - Evidence from a Natural Field Experiment (with P. Arora and A. Jain)</title><link>https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/project/saliency/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/project/saliency/</guid><description>&lt;p>Students often exert low levels of effort on the test, especially in low-stake tests which may paint an incorrect image of their true learning levels. Offering pecuniary and non-pecuniary incentives may be effective in increasing such effort but often not feasible. Increasing the maximum points assigned to the test may be a supposedly irrelevant factor that can frame it as more valued, and nudge students to exert more effort on the test. Using a natural field experiment, we randomly assign 1235 students to a test framed as either carrying maximum 20-points or 100-points, and study its impact in both high-stake (comprising non-risky and one risky question) and low-stake (comprising only non-risky questions) test settings. While we find a small and statistically insignificant average treatment effect in both settings, we find positive treatment effects (1) among lower ability students in a low-stake test, (2) among higher ability students in a high-stake test only when the question carries the risk of a negative penalty. We discuss increased mental effort as the mechanism driving these effects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Working paper available on request&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Impact of terrorism on trust in institutions</title><link>https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/project/trust/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/project/trust/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this project, I examine how exposure to violent environment, like one created in the aftermath of terrorist incidents, alters an individual’s trust in the effectiveness of institutions, such as the country’s parliament, the legal system, the police, the politicians, the political parties, the European Parliament, and the United Nations. We employ the variation in time and location of a series of terrorist attacks that occurred in between 2001 and 2017 in different European countries to study their effect on people’s trust. Our results reveal that when an individual is exposed to terrorist attacks that result in human fatality or injury, his/her level of trust in institutions decreases significantly. Also, the effect of exposure to terrorism-related violence wears away with time. We find evidence of spillover effects - an individual’s faith in establishments is negatively influenced by his/her nearby neighboring countries’ terrorism.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Effect of legalizing same-sex marriage on hate crime towards LGBTQ group</title><link>https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/project/lgbt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/project/lgbt/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this project, I investigate the impact of legalizing same sex marriage in the United States on hate crimes motivated by sexual orientation. I use the state level crime data reported by the Uniform Crime Reporting (UCR) Program of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) from 1996 to 2015. Starting from 2004 with Massachusetts, 35 US states had implemented the law legalizing same sex marriage, before the federal law was enforced on June 26, 2015. Exploiting this state level variation in the implementation date, I observe a significant decrease in the specific type of hate crime. To study the law’s effect on social attitude towards the target group, I use the relative frequency of search queries for derogatory terms specific to this group. This data obtained from Google Trends are used a proxy to capture the change in social animus of a particular state.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/admin/config.yml</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/admin/config.yml</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>