<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Immigrants | Ishita Tripathi</title><link>https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/tag/immigrants/</link><atom:link href="https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/tag/immigrants/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Immigrants</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Immigrants</title><link>https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/tag/immigrants/</link></image><item><title>Do Historical Agro-Ecological Factors Agro-Ecological Factors Shape Attitudes Towards Women’s Rights and Abilities?</title><link>https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/project/ier23/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/project/ier23/</guid><description>&lt;!-- [Link](https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S026499932200205X) -->
&lt;p>A growing strand of literature documents how historical agricultural and ecological factors continue to determine women&amp;rsquo;s role and well-being in society through cultural transmission even today. Studies have shown that such factors are significantly associated with perceptions regarding women&amp;rsquo;s right to jobs and their abilities as political leaders. However, scant attention has been paid to women&amp;rsquo;s ability as business executives and their democratic rights. Using individual level observations from multiple waves of the World Values Survey, this paper investigates whether these historical and ecological factors can explain perceptions regarding women&amp;rsquo;s democratic rights and their ability as business executives. Overall, our findings support the existing literature and show that historical agricultural and ecological factors (ancestral plough use, Neolithic transition, and ancestral resource endowments) have a much broader impact on women&amp;rsquo;s rights and abilities in diverse contexts including the labor force, business, and politics. Given the robustness of this phenomenon, it calls for broad affirmative action favoring women in different social spheres.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Are terrorists responsible for anti-immigrant sentiments? Evidence from Europe</title><link>https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/project/antiimmigrant/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/project/antiimmigrant/</guid><description>&lt;!-- [Link](https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S026499932200205X) -->
&lt;p>Anti-immigrant sentiments are rising across the globe, influencing electoral results, economic policies, labour market outcomes, and even businesses. The factors influencing such sentiments range from socio-economic to cultural. In this paper, I study the impact of one such random shock – terrorism, on anti-immigrant attitudes. I utilise the variation in time and location of terrorist attacks to identify their effect. For this, I analyse the opinions of more than 250,000 individuals belonging to 32 European countries over the period 2002 to 2019. I find that there is around 4 percent decrease on average in an individual&amp;rsquo;s pro-immigrant attitudes after foreigners have carried out terrorist attacks in their country. But this detrimental effect disappears after 6 months and is more localised. My findings imply that inspite of being a relatively rare experience, exposure to terrorism can briefly prejudice an individual against immigrants, but only when the perpetrator(s) is of a different nationality. This can be helpful in understanding the factors leading to increased animosity against migrants.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Impact of terrorism on trust in institutions</title><link>https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/project/trust/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/project/trust/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this project, I examine how exposure to violent environment, like one created in the aftermath of terrorist incidents, alters an individual’s trust in the effectiveness of institutions, such as the country’s parliament, the legal system, the police, the politicians, the political parties, the European Parliament, and the United Nations. We employ the variation in time and location of a series of terrorist attacks that occurred in between 2001 and 2017 in different European countries to study their effect on people’s trust. Our results reveal that when an individual is exposed to terrorist attacks that result in human fatality or injury, his/her level of trust in institutions decreases significantly. Also, the effect of exposure to terrorism-related violence wears away with time. We find evidence of spillover effects - an individual’s faith in establishments is negatively influenced by his/her nearby neighboring countries’ terrorism.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>