<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Trust | Ishita Tripathi</title><link>https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/tag/trust/</link><atom:link href="https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/tag/trust/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Trust</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Trust</title><link>https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/tag/trust/</link></image><item><title>Can terrorism diminish public confidence in institutions? Evidence from European countries</title><link>https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/project/trust/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/project/trust/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this project, I examine how exposure to violent environment, like one created in the aftermath of terrorist incidents, alters an individual’s trust in the effectiveness of institutions, such as the country’s parliament, the legal system, the police, the politicians, the political parties, the European Parliament, and the United Nations. We employ the variation in time and location of a series of terrorist attacks that occurred in between 2001 and 2017 in different European countries to study their effect on people’s trust. Our results reveal that when an individual is exposed to terrorist attacks that result in human fatality or injury, his/her level of trust in institutions decreases significantly. Also, the effect of exposure to terrorism-related violence wears away with time. We find evidence of spillover effects - an individual’s faith in establishments is negatively influenced by his/her nearby neighboring countries’ terrorism.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Do public welfare projects reduce or instigate civil unrest? A study in India</title><link>https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/project/naxal/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ishita-tripathi.github.io/project/naxal/</guid><description>&lt;p>Left-wing extremism (LWE) and related conflict between insurgents and Government troops have claimed several lives and hampered inclusive development in the last five decades in some eastern, central and southern states in India. Several papers in the field found a strong association between such insurgency and socio-economic deprivation. In that regard, central and state governments have launched several development programs directed towards the affected areas in the last couple of decades. In this project, we plan to use the spatial regression discontinuity model to estimate a relationship between government programs and Maoist/Naxalite insurgency and violence.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>